Guide to the Western Americana Card Photograph File
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Western Americana card photograph file.
1850-1970
1860-1910
WA Photos File
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
circa 1000 photographic prints: b & w; on mounts 22 cm. x 30 cm. or smaller.
This collection consists of card photographs of various sizes and formats, as well as unmounted photographic prints, circa 1851-1965. The collection documents a broad range of commercial photography between 1860 and 1910, mainly created by regional operators and traveling photographers. The collection also includes examples by renowned photographers, such as Frank Jay Haynes, William Henry Jackson, Alexander Martin, Charles Roscoe Savage, Isaiah West Taber, and Carleton E. Watkins.
Yale Collection of Western Americana
Haynes, F. Jay (Frank Jay), 1853-1921
Savage, C. R. (Charles Roscoe), 1832-1909
Taber, I. W. (Isaiah West), 1830-1912
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Acquired from various sources
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
This collection has no permanent box or folder designations for items within it, so patrons should note the photographer and image description when requesting materials
History of the Collection
This collection derives from an illustration file maintained by the staff of the Yale Collection of Western Americana since 1952. The collection has served as a means for bringing together photographic materials acquired singularly and in small groups. Occasionally, a critical mass of photographs by a particular photographer or studio accrue within the collection and becomes the basis for an artificially created collection documenting that individual. This collection continues to embody this dynamic function and groups of photographic material will continue to become the basis of smaller individual collections.
During the late twentieth century, archivists preliminarily arranged and briefly described the collection in a print finding aid. In 2008, the print finding aid served as the basis for a thorough examination and detailed description of the collection.
Prior to 2008, library staff did not routinely document provenance information.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of card photographs of various sizes and formats, as well as unmounted photographic prints. The collection documents a broad range of commercial photography between 1860 and 1910, mainly created by regional operators and traveling photographers. The collection also includes examples by renowned photographers, such as Frank Jay Haynes, William Henry Jackson, Alexander Martin, Charles Roscoe Savage, Isaiah West Taber, and Carleton E. Watkins.
The imagery provides diverse visual documentation of the natural and built environment, as well as portraits of the inhabitants of the American West during the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries. Specific images include informal and studio portraits of American Indians and settlers, as well as views of cities and towns, mining and logging operations, railroads, military installations, agricultural activities, American Indian reservations, and natural scenery in and about the American West.
Image descriptions of photographic prints derive from inscriptions on the verso and recto of the item and from image analysis by the archivist. Descriptions of items in this finding aid include the dimensions of each photographic print in centimeters and the dimensions of its mount (when present) in centimeters. Descriptions usually include information about the working locations of photographer, and occasionally physical characteristics of items, such as image numbers applied by the photographer or inscriptions by a previous owner, as well as contextual information about the image.
Each folder contains a single photographic print, except when noted in the item description.
About Card Photographs
Most of the items in this collection are photographic prints mounted on cardboard, known as card photographs. During the nineteenth century, card photographs were a popular way to present photographic prints, especially carte-de-visite and cabinet photographs. The mounts for card photographs vary in format and dimensions, and the mounted photographic prints vary in technical processes. The photographic prints are usually albumen prints, but also include collodion prints, cyanotypes, gelatin silver prints, platinum prints, and salted paper prints.
Introduced in the United States in 1860, carte-de-visite photographs gain their name from French calling cards. The photographic prints, which usually measure 8.89 x 6.35 cm (2.125 Ã— 3.5 in.), were mounted on cardboard 10 x 6 cm (2.5 X 4.5 in.). Carte-de-visite photographs remained a popular form in the United States into early 1870s, when they were largely replaced by cabinet photographs.
Cabinet photographs are larger than carte-de-visite photographs, usually 9.5 x 13.8 cm (3.5 x 5.5 in.), mounted on cardboard 10.5 x 16.4 cm (4.5 by 6.25 in.). Cabinet cards remained popular during the last two decades of the nineteenth century, as did other sized formats, including boudoir midget mounts, 5.1 x 8.6 cm (2 x 3.375 in.); victoria cards, 8.3 x 12.7 cm (3.25 x 5 in.); promenade photographs, 10.2 x 17.8 cm (4 x 7 in.); boudoir photographs, 13.3 x 21.6 cm (5.25 x 8.5 in.); imperial photographs, 17.5 x 25.1 cm (6.875 x 9.875 in.); and panel photographs, 29.5 x 10.2 cm (8.25 x 4 in.).
Card photograph mounts often have printed or embossed decorations conveying advertisements about the photographer, the studio, and location, as well as awards, areas of expertise, or prominent patrons. Photographers and other individuals, such as the subjects in the image or the collector of it, often wrote descriptive inscriptions about the photograph on the verso or recto of the cardboard mount.
Arrangement
Organized into three series. Series I. Identified Photographers. Series II. Unidentified Photographers. Series III. Oversize.
Given the dynamic nature of this collection, items will move in and out of the collection. The collection has no permanent box or folder designations for items in each series.
Cities and towns -- West (U.S.) -- Pictorial works; Indians of North America -- West (U.S.) -- Pictorial works; Indians of North America -- West (U.S.) -- Portraits; Mineral industries -- West (U.S.) -- Pictorial works; Photographers -- West (U.S.) -- Work; Railroads -- West (U.S.) -- Pictorial works; West (U.S.) -- Pictorial works; Card photographs (photographs); Visiting cards; Cyanotypes (photographic prints); Photographic prints; Tintypes (prints); Yale Collection of Western Americana
- Identified Photographers, circa 1851-1965; Series I; 672
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists of photographic prints and their accompanying mounts that have dimensions less than 22 x 29 cm (8.7 x 11.4 in.) in size and created by identified photographers. Materials with larger dimensions are located in Series III. Oversize.
  Arrangement
  Photographs in this series are arranged in alphabetical order by surname of the photographer or the corporate name of a studio that created them and then chronologically therein.
  - Abell, Frank George, Jr. (1844-1910)
    Biographical/Historical note
    Photographer in Portland, Oregon
    - Copy photograph of a painting of a lake and mountain, possibly Mount Rainier, Washington, circa 1880-1899; 10.4 x 14.5 cm, unmounted (Box 1)
  - Albertstone, Reuben E. G. (born 1841)
    Photographer in Sitka, Alaska
    - Steamer Queen in Alaska, circa 1880-1899; 11.3 x 20.1 cm on mount 13.5 x 21.7 cm (Box 1)
  - Alman & Co.
    Photography studio in New York, New York
    - Studio portrait of C. Blydenburg (sic), circa 1880-1890; 9.3 x 5.4 cm on mount 10.7 x 6.5 cm (Box 1)
      Probably a portrait of Charles Edward Blydenburgh (1854-1921), a justice of the Wyoming State Supreme Court
  - Alter, Charles F. (born 1831)
    Photographer in Cheyenne, Wyoming Territory
    - Krebs Memorial Presbyterian Church, Cheyenne, Wyoming, circa 1870; 9.7 x 5.7 cm on mount 10.2 x 6.1 cm (Box 1)
  - Amian, Brother, attributed
    Brother Amian was a member of the faculty at College of the Christian Brothers of New Mexico (later College of Santa Fe) in Santa Fe, New Mexico
    - Copy photograph of a view of the front of Mission San Miguel, Santa Fe, New Mexico, circa 1872; 14.7 x 10.9 cm on mount 17.8 x 12.7 cm (Box 1)
      Manuscript on verso: "up to 1872"
    - Altar of Mission San Miguel, Santa Fe, New Mexico, circa 1899; 13.0 x 9.9 cm on mount 16.7 x 11.0 cm (Box 1)
      Initials "B. A" printed on mount
    - Gallery of the Mission San Miguel, Santa Fe, New Mexico, circa 1899; 9.6 x 15.2 cm on mount 10.8 x 16.7 cm (Box 1)
      Letterpress caption on verso details "Interesting Items Respecting the San Miguel Church"
    - View of the old front of Mission San Miguel, Santa Fe, New Mexico, circa 1899; 2 photographic prints, 11.2 x 17.9 cm on mount 12.5 x 20.3 cm (Box 1)
      Letterpress caption on verso of one print details "Interesting Items Respecting the San Miguel Church"
  - Andersen, Niels B. (born 1854)
    Photographer in Redwood Falls, Minnesota
    - Studio portrait of a Dakota Indian man, identified as Good Thunder (1819-1901), also known as Walinyanwaste or Andrew Good Thunder, wearing a hat from the Grand Army of the Republic fraternal organization, 1884-1900; Oval 7.1 x 5.1 cm on mount 17.1 x 11.4 cm (Box 1)
    - Copy photograph of a painting of a Dakota Indian man, identified as Good Thunder (1819-1901), also known as Walinyanwaste or Andrew Good Thunder, 1900-1910; 13.3 x 10.2 cm on mount 16.7 x 11.0 cm (Box 1)
  - Anderson
    Photographer in New York, New York
    - Studio portrait of Henry Benjamin Whipple (1822-1901), the first Episcopal bishop of Minnesota., circa 1890-1899; 14.0 x 10.0 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.6 cm (Box 1)
      Newspaper clipping affixed on the verso reports of his death
  - Anderson, Oliver
    Photographer in Seattle, Washington
    - Douglas fir in Ravenna Park, Seattle, Washington, 1902; 16.8 x 11.7 cm, unmounted (Box 1)
      Upper right corner torn away
  - Austin Studio
    Photography studio with locations throughout California
    - Studio portrait of two boys, identified as Raul and Salvador, probably created in the San Francisco studio, 1932 January 31; 24.5 x 17.1 cm in a folder 25.6 x 17.9 cm (Box 1)
      Immediate Source of Acquisition
      Purchased from Bolerium Books on the Arthur Corbitt Hoskins Memorial Fund, 2011
      Ink inscrption in Spanish
  - Baer, Erwin
    Photographer in Prescott, Arizona
    - Jerome Smelter, United Verde Copper Mine, circa 1890; 10.5 x 18.3 cm on mount 13.2 x 21.4 cm (Box 1)
    - Tunnel passage through a rock formation, circa 1890; 11.2 x 18.7 cm on mount 13.4 x 12.7 cm (Box 1)
    - Walnut Grove Dam, Back View After Flood, circa 1890; 10.5 x 16.5 cm on mount 13.2 x 21.4 cm (Box 1)
  - Bailey & Terry
    Photography studio in Palestine, Texas; partnership included F. B. Bailey (born 1830)
    - Residence of Herbert M. Hoxie, 1879; 11.3 x 18.9 cm on mount 13.2 x 21.4 cm (Box 1)
      Hoxie was a general manager of the Texas and Pacific Railway
  - Baker & Johnston
    Photography studio in Evanston, Wyoming
    - Studio portrait of Washakie (circa 1804-1900), Chief of the Shoshone Indians, circa 1890-1899; 16.8 x 10.8 cm on mount 17.8 x 11.4 cm (Box 1)
  - Baker, Frank E. (born 1854)
    Photographer in Greeley, Colorado
    - Potato field of B. S. Pier in Pleasant Valley, Colorado, two and a half miles northeast of Greeley, showing a yield of three hudred bushels to the acre, and digger and sorter in operation, circa 1893; 15.0 x 20.1 cm on mount 20.2 x 25.3 cm (Box 1)
      Manuscript inscription on verso
  - Balster, Frank S.
    Photographer in Durango, Colorado
    - Ute Indian Dance near Durango, Colorado, circa 1890-1899; 11.2 x 19.2 cm on mount 12.8 x 20.4 cm (Box 1)
    - View of Picture Rock, cliff dwellings near Mancos, Colorado, circa 1890-1899; 11.6 x 18.2 cm on mount 12.7 x 20.3 cm (Box 1)
  - Barkalow Brothers
    Photography studio in Denver, Colorado; partnership of Sidney D. Barkalow and Derrick V. Barkalow
    - Grey's and Irvine peaks from the Diamond Job, Kelso Mountain, Colorado, circa 1885-1895; 11.0 x 18.7 cm on mount 12.7 x 10.3 cm (Box 1)
    - View of mines and Silver Plume, Colorado, circa 1885-1895; 11.0 x 18.7 cm on mount 12.7 x 20.3 cm (Box 1)
    - Hanging Rock, Clear Creek Canyon, Colorado Central Railroad, circa 1885-1895; 18.6 x 10.9 cm on mount 20.3 x 12.7 cm (Box 1)
    - High bridge on the Georgetown Loop, Colorado Central Railroad, Georgetown, Colorado, circa 1885-1895; 10.9 x 18.7 cm on mount 12.6 x 20.3 cm (Box 1)
    - Copy photograph of a painting of the Georgetown Loop, Colorado Central Railroad, Georgetown, Colorado, circa 1885-1895; 18.4 x 10.9 cm on mount 20.3 x 12.7 cm (Box 1)
    - View of Idaho Springs, Colorado, circa 1885-1895; 11.1 x 18.7 cm on mount 12.7 x 20.8 cm (Box 1)
  - Barker, Albert W.
    Photographer in Ottawa, Kansas
    - Copy photograph portrait of a Sauk Indian, identified as Moses Keokuk (circa 1821-1903), circa 1869-1870; 8.3 x 5.5 cm on mount 10 x 6.2 cm (Box 1)
      Copy photograph of an image originally created by Antonio Zeno Shindler, March 31, 1868
    - Copy photograph studio portrait a Fox Indian, identified as Wa-Com-Mo, Brave of the Foxes, Kansas, circa 1869-1870; 8.3 x 5.5 cm on mount 10 x 6.2 cm (Box 1)
  - Barnard, Thomas Nathan
    Photographer in Wallace, Idaho
    - An overhead view of the camp of a of the 4th Infantry Regiment of the United States Army in Mullan, Idaho, during the Coeur d'Alene Miners' Strike in Idaho, 1892 July; 2 photographic prints; 15.8 x 21.3 cm on mount trimmed to 15.8 x 21.3 cm, and 16.8 x 21.5 on mount 20.1 x 25.2 cm. (Box 1)
      Purchased from Michael Vinson on the William Robertson Coe Fund No. 3, 2013
  - Barrett, Caroline E. (born 1835)
    Photographer in Fort Dodge, Iowa
    - Studio portrait of two girls and a boy, circa 1870; 9.0 x 5.3 cm on mount 10.1 x 6.1 cm (Box 1)
  - Bass, Edwin A. (1860-1915)
    Photographer in Socorro, New Mexico
    - View of Socorro, New Mexico, circa 1885; 11.5 x 18.5 cm on mount 12.7 x 20.4 cm (Box 1)
    - Landscape with the Magdalena Mountains in background, circa 1885; 10.8 x 18.5 cm on mount 12.8 x 20.4 cm (Box 1)
    - Street and stores in Socorro, New Mexico, circa 1885; 11.0 x 16.4 cm on mount 12.7 x 20.4 cm (Box 1)
  - Bates & Muhr
    Photography studio in Denver, Colorado; partnership of Adolph Muhr and William L. Bates
    - Platte Canal in Platte Canyon, Colorado, 1883; 14.2 x 10.2 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.8 cm (Box 1)
      Information on irrigation and an advertisement for Platte Land Company on verso
  - Baumann & Meddaugh
    Photography studio in Rushville, Nebraska
    - View of Rushville, Nebraska, 1891 Jan 13; 12.0 x 19.4 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.4 cm (Box 1)
  - Beals, Albert J.
    Photographer in Gold Hill, Nevada
    - Studio portrait of a man, 1867; 8.9 x 5.7 cm on mount 10.1 x 6.2 cm (Box 1)
  - Bell, Annie, attributed
    Photographer in Washington, District of Columbia; widow of Charles Milton Bell, she managed his studio after his death in 1893 until 1909
    - Group studio portrait of the Cherokee Indian delegates to Washington, District of Columbia, 1894; 18.5 x 23.5 cm on mount 20.2 x 25.2 cm (Box 1)
      Manuscript inscriptions on mount
  - Bell, Charles Milton (1848-1893)
    Photographer in Washington, District of Columbia
    - Studio portrait of Iron Nation, a Dakota Brulé Indian, in partial native dress and holding a blanket, during a visit to Washington, District of Columbia, in the winter of 1880-1881., 13.9 x 9.8 cm on mount 16.5 x 10.8 cm (Box 1)
  - Black Hills Studios, Inc
    Photography studio in Deadwood, South Dakota
    - '76ers all - honorary pallbearers in front of the cabin of Richard "Deadwood Dick" Clarke in Deadwood, South Dakota, 1930 May; 20.5 x 25.5 cm, unmounted (Box 1)
      Manuscript inscription on verso: "Day of Deadwood Dick's funeral"
  - Black, James Wallace
    Photographer in Boston, Massachusetts
    - Studio portrait of Kiasiwa, a Zuni Indian Priest, circa 1882; 14.5 x 10 cm on mount 16.4 x 12.7 cm (Box 1)
    - Studio portrait of Liayuahtsailunkya, a Zuni Indian Priest, circa 1882; 14.5 x 10 cm on mount 16.4 x 12.7 cm (Box 1)
  - Blakesley, H. H.
    Photographer in North Platte, Nebraska
    - View of the Citizens Bank and McWilliams & Co. Land Office, circa 1885-1895; 10.1 x 14.4 cm on mount 10.1 x 16.3 cm (Box 1)
  - Blanchard, J. B. & Co., photographers
    Photography studio in Los Angeles, California
    - Pepper Tree Drive, Central Park, Los Angeles, California, circa 1895; 11.3 x 19.3 cm on mount 13.2 x 21.4 cm (Box 1)
    - In Sixth Street Park, The Kiosk, Los Angeles, California, circa 1895; 11.4 x 19.6 cm on mount 13.2 x 21.5 cm (Box 1)
    - Third Street Looking West from Hill, Los Angeles, California, circa 1895; 18.5 x 11.9 cm on mount 21.3 x 13.2 cm (Box 1)
    - Old Fan Palm, Lyon Street, Near Aliso Street, Los Angeles, California, circa 1895; 18.6 x 11.8 cm on mount 21.5 x 13.3 cm (Box 1)
  - Blank & Stoller
    - Studio portrait of William Robertson Coe (1869-1955), circa 1950; 25.8 x 20.3 cm on mount 28.1 x 21.8 cm (Box 1)
  - Bogardus, Abraham
    - Studio portrait of H. D. Blydenburgh with rifle, circa 1877-1878; 19.9 x 12.1 cm on mount 21.5 x 13.3 cm (Box 2)
      H. D. Blydenburgh was an avid long rifle sharpshooter, a member of the New York Rifle Club, and participated in rifle competitions in New York, New York. He was a brother of Charles E. Blydenburgh (1854-1921)
    - Studio portrait of James S. Conlin with rifle, circa 1877-1878; 21.1 x 11.9 cm on mount 21.5 x 13.3 cm (Box 2)
      James S. Conlin was an avid long rifle sharpshooter, a member of the New York Rifle Club, and participated in rifle competitions in New York, New York. He was a friend of Charles E. Blydenburgh (1854-1921)
  - Bogrand, Peter
    Photographer in Marshfield, Wisconsin
    - Studio portrait of Emeline L. Fuller, author of Left By The Indians (1892)., circa 1890; 8.9 x 6.0 cm on mount 10.5 x 6.4 cm (Box 2)
  - Boorne & May
    Photography studio in Calgary, Northwest Territory (Alberta); partnership of William Hanson Boorne and Ernest Gundry May
    - Cascade Mountain, Alberta, Canada, circa 1886-1893; 11.6 x 19.2 cm on mount 12.6 x 20.2 cm (Box 2)
  - Booth, W. I.
    Photographer in Goldfield, Nevada
    - Panoramic photograph of Tonopah, Nevada, looking east, circa 1904; 2 photographic prints, 16.1 x 23.5 cm and smaller on mounts 20.1 x 25.2 cm (Box 2)
      Purchased from Michael Vinson on the Frederick W. and Carrie S. Beinecke Fund for Western Americana, 2010
      Two photographs that form a panoramic view of Tonopah, Nevada. A printed label and inscriptions in the negative identify mines, as well as Main Street, the Tonopah Company office, a residence of the Tonopah Company, the Butler Building, a Catholic Church, and a school house
  - Boston, Jacob Adam
    - Group of American Indians dancing in front of the Longfellow School Building, Durango, Colorado, circa 1890 Sep-Oct; 9.9 x 14.2 cm on mount 10.9 x 16.5 cm (Box 2)
    - Group of American Indians dancing opposite the Strater Hotel, Durango, Colorado, circa 1890 Sep-Oct; 10.2 x 15.1 cm on mount 10.7 x 16.9 cm (Box 2)
  - Boughton, G. B.
    Photographer in Decatur, Michigan
    - Studio portrait of a man, identified as Mr. Huyck, circa 1870; 9.2 x 5.8 cm on mount 10.1 x 6.2 cm (Box 2)
  - Bowers, W. T.
    Photographer in Lynn, Massachusetts
    - Copy photograph of a studio portrait of Reverend Elkanah Walker (1805-1877), 9.4 x 5.9 cm on mount 10.0 x 6.4 cm (Box 2)
      Reverend Walker and his wife, Mary Richardson Walker (1811-1897) operated the a mission for the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions at Tshimakain, about twenty-five miles northwest of Spokane, Washington, from 1838-1848
  - Boyd & Braas
    Photography studio in Seattle, Washington; partnership of George H. Braas and William F. Boyd
    - Indian hop pickers, circa 1889; 11.0 x 18.5 cm, unmounted (Box 2)
    - Indian hop pickers, circa 1889; 11.3 x 17.5 cm, unmounted (Box 2)
    - Copy photograph of a studio portrait of Chief Seattle, chief of the Suquamish and Duwamish Indians, originally created in 1864, circa 1895; 14.0 x 10.0 cm on mount 16.6 x 10.9 cm (Box 2)
      2 photographic prints
    - Copy photograph of studio portrait of Kikisoblu (circa 1820-1896), circa 1896; 14.0 x 10.1 cm on mount 16.6 x 10.9 cm (Box 2)
      Kikisoblu, also known as Wewick or Princess Angeline, was the eldest daughter of Chief Seattle (chief of the Suquamish and Duwamish Indians)
      Image originally created by Edward Sheriff Curtis (1868-1952)
      Manuscript on verso: "Compliments of Dr. W. Johnson, Ballard, Wash"
  - Boyd, William F.
    - Front Street, south from Columbia in Seattle, Washington, after the fire on June 6, 1889, 1889 Jun; 11.1 x 18.6 cm on paper mount 11.9 x 18.7 cm (Box 2)
  - Brack, Asa A.
    Photographer in San Antonio, Texas
    - Copy photograph of a painted portrait of David Crockett (1786-1836), 1889-1892; 14.2 x 9.9 cm on mount 16.6 x 10.9 cm (Box 2)
    - Mission Nuestra Señora de la Purisima Concepcion de Acuña Mission in San Antonio, Texas, 1892-1893; 11.3 x 18.2 cm on mount 12.0 x 18.7 cm (Box 2)
      Printed descriptions of San Antonio's missions on verso
  - Brackett, William S.
    Photographer in Lewiston, Idaho
    - Steel wagon bridge a cross Snake River at Lewiston, Idaho, circa 1900; 11.9 x 16.8 cm on mount 17.6 x 22.9 cm (Box 2)
  - Bradley & Rulofson
    Photography studio in San Francisco, California; partnership of Henry William Bradley (1813-1891) and William Herman Rulofson (1826-1878)
    - Studio portrait of Albert Kautz (1839-1907), Lieutenant Commander, United States Navy, circa 1870; 8.7 x 5.5 cm on mount 10.1 x 6.2 cm (Box 2)
    - Studio portrait of D. L. Bartlett, 1873; 15.1 x 10.4 cm on mount 16.7 x 10.7 cm (Box 2)
    - Composite photograph of steamship pioneers, circa 1874; 20.2 x 25.5 cm, unmounted (Box 2)
    - Composite photograph of members of the San Francisco Bohemian Club, circa 1876; 10.2 x 15.8 cm on mount 10.8 x 16.5 cm (Box 2)
      Members of club identified on verso
    - Studio portrait of George N. Cahill, circa 1880-1890; 10.1 x 14.4 cm on mount 10.9 x 16.6 cm (Box 2)
    - Studio portrait of P. D. Moore, a resident of Olympia, circa 1880-1890; 8.9 x 5.5 cm on mount 9.6 x 6.2 cm (Box 2)
  - Brady, Mathew B. (circa 1823-1896)
    - Studio portrait of an American Indian woman, probably a member of a Southern Plains Indian delegation, circa 1863; 14.5 x 10.0 cm on mount 15.8 x 10.8 cm (Box 2)
  - Brewster, John Calvin
    Photographer in Ventura, California
    - View of Ventura, California, circa 1887; 11.8 x 20.1 cm on mount 13.1 x 21.5 cm (Box 2)
  - Brisbois, Alfred
    Photographer in Leadville, Colorado
    - St. George's Church, Leadville, Colorado, circa 1881-1892; 10.9 x 18.7 cm on mount 12.7 x 20.3 cm (Box 2)
    - View of Douglas City, Colorado, from Hagerman Mine Tunnel, circa 1881-1892; 11.0 x 18.8 cm on mount 12.7 x 20.3 cm (Box 2)
    - Waterfall at Chalk Ranch near Leadville, Colorado, circa 1881-1892; 18.8 x 10.9 cm on mount 20.3 x 12.7 cm (Box 2)
  - Brown, C. B.
    Photographer in Minot, North Dakota
    - Group of American Indian male students at the Fort Berthold Indian School; four students aim rifles at an American Indian man wearing a feathered headdress, circa 1890; 11.5 x 19.3 cm on mount 13.3 x 21.6 cm (Box 2)
      Gift of Michael Vinson, 2011
      The Fort Berthold Indian School was established in the former buildings of Fort Stevenson, 1883-1894
  - Brown, Ernest
    Photographer in Edmonton, Alberta
    - View from the Cliff House, Edmonton, Alberta, 1926-1927; 12.5 x 20.1 cm, unmounted (Box 2)